My name's Ryan Parker with Parker Home Renovations in New Braunfels, Texas, and today I'm going to teach you how to replace a cabinet door hinge.
If you have a cabinet door hinge that is either fallen off or bent or is rusted shut at your house, you may have to replace it.
Now the first thing you're going to want to do is you want to take a look at the hinge that is currently on the door and try to find one that's similar to it, that will fit in the same application.
These hinges here you can get at just about any, any local hardware store and these are very good hinges to keep the door shut and they're very sturdy and very strong.
Now what you're going to want to do is you're going to want to take the old hinges off the door.
Now, once you take the old hinges off the door, you're not going to be able to use the existing holes where the screws go because those holes may be stripped out or you want to find new wood to screw to so the hinges will hold better.
Now what you do is you'll mount the hinge on the back of the cabinet door two inches from the top of the door, two inches from the bottom of the door on the hinge side.
You'll want to slide it into place, and you'll want to pop a screw in each one of these holes here on the back of the door.
Now once you get both hinges put on the top and on the bottom of the door, you'll want to hold the door in place.
Now this hinge here mounts on the outside of the facing of the cabinet.
So you'll hold the door in place, and then you'll line it up with the other doors and then you'll pop a screw in the top and the bottom of each hinge.
My name's Ryan Parker with Parker Home Renovations.
And that's how you fix a door hinge.
You can visit me at parkerhomerenovations.com.